In the twenty years since His Grace King William became the ruler of England,
he has seen fit to grant land to those lords and churchmen
who supported him against the claims of the usurper, Earl Harold.
The time has now come for a reckoning.
As the King's commissioners,
we have been commanded to travel throughout the realm
to make sure that not one single hide of land is overlooked.
That not one pig or villager remains uncounted.
To ensure an accurate survey,
each manor will be visited by two different sets of commissioners;
the second group to confirm the reports of the first.
And in order that there might be no question of fraud,
each commissioner will only survey those parts of the country
where he owns no land or other property.
We shall see to it
that the King receives those taxes that are due to him,
and woe betide anyone who tries to deceive us.